<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>品森</title>
  <subtitle>一人的呓语</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://spencerpomme.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-20T13:01:08.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://spencerpomme.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>工常邵</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wordlist Story 1</title>
    <link href="http://spencerpomme.github.io/2016/04/20/Wordlist%20Story%201/"/>
    <id>http://spencerpomme.github.io/2016/04/20/Wordlist Story 1/</id>
    <published>2016-04-20T12:39:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-20T13:01:08.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;####Chapter one (not finished)&lt;br&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;underground&lt;/strong&gt; world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything changed the day my foster parents took me out of that &lt;strong&gt;frigid&lt;/strong&gt; orphanage, the place was much more a place for &lt;strong&gt;contrition&lt;/strong&gt; than parentless children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;unidimensional&lt;/strong&gt; world is not lifeless. If I’m being &lt;strong&gt;retentive&lt;/strong&gt; and still have the mental &lt;strong&gt;agility&lt;/strong&gt;, it could be a long story that may &lt;strong&gt;overwhelm&lt;/strong&gt; you with the details. However, I have such an &lt;strong&gt;infamous&lt;/strong&gt; memory that I may &lt;strong&gt;jeopardize&lt;/strong&gt; the accuracy of the story if I &lt;strong&gt;unscrupulous&lt;/strong&gt;ly fabricate the parts those seem blurred to me. In order to be &lt;strong&gt;dutiful&lt;/strong&gt; storyteller, it better be terse. Don’t worry, it’s not going to be an &lt;strong&gt;insipid&lt;/strong&gt; one though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was about seventy years ago that I got &lt;strong&gt;adopt&lt;/strong&gt;ed by a couple who are both scientists. I used to be a &lt;strong&gt;flabby&lt;/strong&gt; boy back then and as a result got beaten up a lot by bullies in the orphanage, the &lt;strong&gt;Clemency&lt;/strong&gt; of Jesus state orphanage. This experience may be the cause of the &lt;strong&gt;fickleness&lt;/strong&gt; in my personality since I always felt my future was &lt;strong&gt;chancy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;devoid&lt;/strong&gt; of hope. Everything changed the day my step parents took me out of that &lt;strong&gt;frigid&lt;/strong&gt; orphanage, the place was much more a place for &lt;strong&gt;contrition&lt;/strong&gt; than parentless children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My foster father was a &lt;strong&gt;prestigious&lt;/strong&gt; physicist and Marry, my foster mother, was also a physicist as well as a profound engineer. For a long time, we lived a &lt;strong&gt;spartan&lt;/strong&gt; life in a villa located on the &lt;strong&gt;ridge&lt;/strong&gt; of a dead volcano that its &lt;strong&gt;crater&lt;/strong&gt; is within a hundred yard from our front door. It’s &lt;strong&gt;nonthreatening&lt;/strong&gt;, of course. The &lt;strong&gt;alienation&lt;/strong&gt; from mainstream society could be a &lt;strong&gt;boon&lt;/strong&gt; to someone &lt;strong&gt;agoraphobic&lt;/strong&gt;, but not to an ten-year-old boy. Very soon, my &lt;strong&gt;congenital&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;proclivity&lt;/strong&gt; for exploration was &lt;strong&gt;galvanize&lt;/strong&gt;d. One &lt;strong&gt;sultry&lt;/strong&gt; afternoon of August 18th 1946, I had a conversation with my father which lead to the start of our story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Papa, are we &lt;strong&gt;derelict&lt;/strong&gt;s of modern society?” I asked in a &lt;strong&gt;disgruntled&lt;/strong&gt; voice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh my little Pinsent, where does this &lt;strong&gt;platitudinous&lt;/strong&gt; remark come from?”, my father seems a little surprised as well as amused. He untied the &lt;strong&gt;buckle&lt;/strong&gt; of a machine which was used to &lt;strong&gt;irradiate&lt;/strong&gt; some ore and the experiment stopped. As he turned face to me the glow of the ore ceased in an &lt;strong&gt;anticlimactic&lt;/strong&gt; way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Is it because of &lt;strong&gt;defamation&lt;/strong&gt;s those &lt;strong&gt;vitriolic&lt;/strong&gt; people spread about you and mama or they trying to &lt;strong&gt;encumber&lt;/strong&gt; your work?” I jump up to papa’s desk, sitting &lt;strong&gt;abreast&lt;/strong&gt; that &lt;strong&gt;elaborate&lt;/strong&gt; machine. “Mama told me that they even &lt;strong&gt;excise&lt;/strong&gt;d you from the academy, it’s &lt;strong&gt;implausible&lt;/strong&gt;!” I murmured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Son, someday you may realize that being &lt;strong&gt;supplant&lt;/strong&gt;ed is not necessarily a &lt;strong&gt;punishment&lt;/strong&gt; but to gain &lt;strong&gt;opulent&lt;/strong&gt; amount of free time. As long as one belongs to a certain organization he has to show &lt;strong&gt;conformity&lt;/strong&gt;, otherwise you might be considered a haughty and immature person.” My father responded in a &lt;strong&gt;sedate&lt;/strong&gt; voice, looked me in the eye. It was like he was trying to &lt;strong&gt;engrave&lt;/strong&gt; this into my head, but then he smiled, with understanding of his son’s boredom, “Do you want to know what this &lt;strong&gt;outmoded&lt;/strong&gt; machine is?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What? Outmoded… Then what is it, papa? &lt;em&gt;Who&lt;/em&gt; made it?” I couldn’t move away my eyes from that &lt;strong&gt;dumbbell-like&lt;/strong&gt; machine, which seems &lt;strong&gt;unworldly&lt;/strong&gt; that not likely to be created by man. My father was a physicist with &lt;strong&gt;talent&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;towering&lt;/strong&gt; acadamical achievements, this is one thing. But this machine? It’s just so &lt;strong&gt;deviant&lt;/strong&gt; for a scientific equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want to &lt;strong&gt;disillusion&lt;/strong&gt; you, my son. But it was just a gift from an &lt;strong&gt;anterior&lt;/strong&gt; friend. That friend of mine tried to &lt;strong&gt;provoke&lt;/strong&gt; me by sending a &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; that nobody knows what it is and where it comes from.” He frowned, “Last several years I was haunted by &lt;strong&gt;self-doubt&lt;/strong&gt; that I may never be able to reveal its &lt;strong&gt;inherent&lt;/strong&gt; nature. Of course I have some &lt;strong&gt;hypotheses&lt;/strong&gt;, but all of them lack of &lt;strong&gt;corroboration&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far I as can remember, my father never tended to &lt;strong&gt;deplore&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;comic&lt;/strong&gt; act of his &lt;strong&gt;immature&lt;/strong&gt; friend, in &lt;strong&gt;inverse&lt;/strong&gt; he was so &lt;strong&gt;possessed&lt;/strong&gt; of digging out its secret which seemed &lt;strong&gt;undecipherable&lt;/strong&gt; as if he had a &lt;strong&gt;rival&lt;/strong&gt; to compete with. He had never been such a &lt;strong&gt;zealot&lt;/strong&gt;, but for some time even my mother thought he’s a “strange machine &lt;strong&gt;fanatic&lt;/strong&gt;“. My mother may preserved an appearance of &lt;strong&gt;nonchalance&lt;/strong&gt;, but her &lt;strong&gt;insight&lt;/strong&gt; far &lt;strong&gt;transcend&lt;/strong&gt;s my fahter’s. With a &lt;strong&gt;cursory&lt;/strong&gt; glance she drawed a conclusion that this machine must be alien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How can you be so sure,” My father asked on dinner table later that day, “You need to do &lt;strong&gt;repetitive&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;reaffirmations&lt;/strong&gt; before &lt;strong&gt;repudiating&lt;/strong&gt; my &lt;strong&gt;hypothesis&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To be continued…)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;####Chapter one (not finished)&lt;br&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;underground&lt;/strong&gt; world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything changed the day my foster parents
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="英语" scheme="http://spencerpomme.github.io/categories/%E8%8B%B1%E8%AF%AD/"/>
    
    
      <category term="GRE" scheme="http://spencerpomme.github.io/tags/GRE/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>c多文件编译的命令行方法（gcc）</title>
    <link href="http://spencerpomme.github.io/2016/04/17/c%E5%A4%9A%E6%96%87%E4%BB%B6%E7%BC%96%E8%AF%91%E7%9A%84%E5%91%BD%E4%BB%A4%E8%A1%8C%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95%EF%BC%88gcc%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>http://spencerpomme.github.io/2016/04/17/c多文件编译的命令行方法（gcc）/</id>
    <published>2016-04-17T07:27:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-04-18T06:34:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;之前在学习数据结构的时候（现在还没有学完orz）发现，其实学习到后边的树、图之类的数据结构的时候，经常会用到stack和queue这两个更为基础的数据结构，需要经常性地包含它们的头文件。一直以来都直接用IDE来做这个事情，直到有一天觉得每次做题都要新建一个工程然后添加文件很麻烦，就决定把常用数据结构的.c和.h放在一个文件夹里，题目做完了就把problem.c放到这个文件夹里用命令行编译一下就得了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;其实挺起来好像还是挺麻烦的，不过就当作是增添一项新经验也好。具体做法如下：（以stack.c和stack.h为例）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;把需要一起变一的文件都放入一个directory里边去&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;cmd/powershell(windows平台)进行如下操作：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; gcc -std=c99 stack.c problem.c -o main&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这样在文件夹里就会出现一个名为main.exe的文件了。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;之前在学习数据结构的时候（现在还没有学完orz）发现，其实学习到后边的树、图之类的数据结构的时候，经常会用到stack和queue这两个更为基础的数据结构，需要经常性地包含它们的头文件。一直以来都直接用IDE来做这个事情，直到有一天觉得每次做题都要新建一个工程然后添加文件很
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="CS" scheme="http://spencerpomme.github.io/categories/CS/"/>
    
    
      <category term="gcc" scheme="http://spencerpomme.github.io/tags/gcc/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
